<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record><pa>20113293465</pa><bibl><it>Journal article</it><au><au1>Malenica, N.</au1><au2>&#352;imon, S.</au2><au3>Besendorfer, V.</au3><au4>Maleti&#263;, E.</au4><au5>Konti&#263;, J. K.</au5><au6>Peji&#263;, I.</au6></au><do>Naturwissenschaften</do><et>Whole genome amplification and microsatellite genotyping of herbarium DNA revealed the identity of an ancient grapevine cultivar.</et><pb>Springer Berlin</pb><lp>Heidelberg</lp><cp>Germany</cp><yr>2011</yr><vl>98</vl><no>9</no><pp>763-772</pp><sn>0028-1042</sn><la>English</la><ur>http://www.springerlink.com/content/b161077101100317/</ur><oi>10.1007/s00114-011-0826-8</oi><re>35 ref.</re><aa>Faculty of Science, Department of Molecular Biology, University of Zagreb, Horvatovac 102a, 10000 Zagreb, Croatia.</aa><em>malenica@zg.biol.pmf.hr</em></bibl><ab>Reconstruction of the grapevine cultivation history has advanced tremendously during the last decade. Identification of grapevine cultivars by using microsatellite DNA markers has mostly become a routine. The parentage of several renowned grapevine cultivars, like Cabernet Sauvignon and Chardonnay, has been elucidated. However, the assembly of a complete grapevine genealogy is not yet possible because missing links might no longer be in cultivation or are even extinct. This problem could be overcome by analyzing ancient DNA from grapevine herbarium specimens and other historical remnants of once cultivated varieties. Here, we present the first successful genotyping of a grapevine herbarium specimen and the identification of the corresponding grapevine cultivar. Using a set of nine grapevine microsatellite markers, in combination with a whole genome amplification procedure, we found the 90-year-old Tribidrag herbarium specimen to display the same microsatellite profile as the popular American cultivar Zinfandel. This work, together with information from several historical documents, provides a new clue of Zinfandel cultivation in Croatia as early as the beginning of fifteenth century, under the native name Tribidrag. Moreover, it emphasizes substantial information potential of existing grapevine and other herbarium collections worldwide.</ab><index><de>genetic markers\genomes\genotypes\grapes\microsatellites</de><id>minisatellites\Vitaceae</id><od>Vitidaceae\Vitis\Vitis vinifera</od><gl>Croatia</gl><up>Vitidaceae\Rhamnales\dicotyledons\angiosperms\Spermatophyta\plants\eukaryotes\Vitis\Balkans\Southern Europe\Europe\Developed Countries\Mediterranean Region</up><cc>FF003\FF020\ZZ360</cc><sc>7B\0C\0P\CA\HO\PL</sc></index><ex>20141111</ex><co>&#109; 2014 CAB International</co></record>
