<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record><an>0E09912846\7H02202567</an><pa>20113293464</pa><bibl><it>Journal article</it><au><au1>Lu, Y. J.</au1><au2>Beeman, R. W.</au2><au3>Campbell, J. F.</au3><au4>Park, Y. S.</au4><au5>Aikins, M. J.</au5><au6>Mori, K.</au6><au7>Akasaka, K.</au7><au8>Tamogami, S.</au8><au9>Phillips, T. W.</au9></au><do>Naturwissenschaften</do><et>Anatomical localization and stereoisomeric composition of Tribolium castaneum aggregation pheromones.</et><pb>Springer Berlin</pb><lp>Heidelberg</lp><cp>Germany</cp><yr>2011</yr><vl>98</vl><no>9</no><pp>755-761</pp><sn>0028-1042</sn><la>English</la><ur>http://www.springerlink.com/content/076754342x12v866/</ur><oi>10.1007/s00114-011-0824-x</oi><re>24 ref.</re><aa>Department of Entomology, Kansas State University, Manhattan, KS 66506, USA.</aa><em>twp1@ksu.edu</em></bibl><ab>We report that the abdominal epidermis and associated tissues are the predominant sources of male-produced pheromones in the red flour beetle, Tribolium castaneum and, for the first time, describe the stereoisomeric composition of the natural blend of isomers of the aggregation pheromone 4,8-dimethyldecanal (DMD) in this important pest species. Quantitative analyses via gas chromatography-mass spectrometry showed that the average amount of DMD released daily by single feeding males of T. castaneum was 878&#177;72 ng (SE). Analysis of different body parts identified the abdominal epidermis as the major source of aggregation pheromone; the thorax was a minor source, while no DMD was detectable in the head. No internal organs or obvious male-specific glands were associated with pheromone deposition. Complete separation of all four stereoisomers of DMD was achieved following oxidation to the corresponding acid, derivatization with (1R, 2R)- and (1S, 2S)-2-(anthracene-2,3-dicarboximido)cyclohexanol to diastereomeric esters, and their separation on reversed-phase high-performance liquid chromatography at &#45;54&#176;C. Analysis of the hexane eluate from Porapak-Q-collected volatiles from feeding males revealed the presence of all four isomers (4R,8R)/(4R,8S)/(4S,8R)/(4S,8S) at a ratio of approximately 4:4:1:1. A walking orientation bioassay in a wind tunnel with various blends of the four synthetic isomers further indicated that the attractive potency of the reconstituted natural blend of 4:4:1:1 was equivalent to that of the natural pheromone and greater than that of the 1:1 blend of (4R,8R)/(4R,8S) used in commercial lures.</ab><index><de>abdomen\animal anatomy\head\insect pests\pheromones\plant pests\thorax</de><id>body components\pest insects</id><od>insects\Tribolium castaneum</od><up>Hexapoda\arthropods\invertebrates\animals\eukaryotes\Tribolium\Tenebrionidae\Coleoptera\insects</up><cc>FF620\YY100</cc><sc>0E\7H\CA\PE\QF</sc></index><ex>20141111</ex><co>&#109; 2014 CAB International</co></record>
