<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record><an>0E09912363</an><pa>20113293463</pa><bibl><it>Journal article</it><au><au1>Hartke, T. R.</au1><au2>Rosengaus, R. B.</au2></au><do>Naturwissenschaften</do><et>Heterospecific pairing and hybridization between Nasutitermes corniger and N. ephratae.</et><pb>Springer Berlin</pb><lp>Heidelberg</lp><cp>Germany</cp><yr>2011</yr><vl>98</vl><no>9</no><pp>745-753</pp><sn>0028-1042</sn><la>English</la><ur>http://www.springerlink.com/content/a2j5707361514152/</ur><oi>10.1007/s00114-011-0823-y</oi><re>49 ref.</re><aa>Northeastern University Biology Department, 134 Mugar Hall, 360 Huntington Avenue, Boston, MA 02115, USA.</aa><em>t.hartke@neu.edu</em></bibl><ab>The sympatric neotropical termites Nasutitermes corniger and Nasutitermes ephratae are clearly distinguishable based on morphology, nest architecture, defensive secretion composition, and molecular markers. However, given the extensive ecological, geographical, and behavioral overlap of these closely related species, the potential for interbreeding may exist. To explore this possibility, heterospecific pairs were formed experimentally to examine courtship and colony-establishment behaviors, and reproductive potential. Courtship and nest construction behavior occurred in heterospecific pairs in a similar manner to that of conspecific pairs. Survival of pairs depended upon the species of the female partner. N. ephratae females paired with N. corniger males produced as many offspring as conspecific pairs. N. corniger females mated to N. ephratae males, however, produced significantly fewer offspring at 60 days post-establishment than the reciprocal cross or conspecific N. ephratae or N. corniger pairs. This was also the only pairing in which any aggression was observed. Heterospecific pairs and groups formed in mate choice mesocosms, suggesting that species recognition between these two termites is not an important aspect of mate choice. Overall, species mismatch tolerance and hybrid offspring viability are high. The present data, together with previous evidence from defensive secretions and isozyme analysis, suggest that hybridization may periodically occur in nature, and that reproductive barriers between these two species may be incomplete. Hybridization could provide a rare but important source of genetic diversity and may ensure mating opportunities for the more abundant sex of alates in each species.</ab><index><de>animal behaviour\behaviour\genetic diversity\genetic variation\hybridization\mating</de><id>animal behavior\behavior\genetic variability\genotypic variability\genotypic variation\Nasutitermes corniger\Nasutitermes ephratae</id><od>Nasutitermes</od><up>Termitidae\Isoptera\insects\Hexapoda\arthropods\invertebrates\animals\eukaryotes\Nasutitermes</up><cc>YY300\YY500</cc><sc>0E\CA\PE</sc></index><ex>20141111</ex><co>&#109; 2014 CAB International</co></record>
