<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record><an>0M09009545\0C08201076</an><pa>20113293477</pa><bibl><it>Journal article</it><au><au1>Atta, S.</au1><au2>Liu YongQing</au2><au3>Cao MengJi</au3><au4>Yang FangYun</au4><au5>Zhou Yan</au5><au6>Zhou ChangYong</au6></au><av>Liu, Y. Q.\Cao, M. J.\Yang, F. Y.\Zhou, Y.\Zhou, C. Y.</av><do>African Journal of Biotechnology</do><et>Molecular characterization of Citrus tristeza virus isolates from Pakistan based on CPG/Hinf I restriction fragment length polymorphism (RFLP) groups analysis.</et><pb>Academic Journals</pb><lp>Nairobi</lp><cp>Kenya</cp><yr>2011</yr><vl>10</vl><no>44</no><pp>8689-8694</pp><sn>1684-5315</sn><la>English</la><ur>http://www.academicjournals.org/AJB/PDF/pdf2011/15Aug/Atta%20et%20al.pdf</ur><re>23 ref.</re><aa>National Citrus Engineering Research Center, Southwest University, Chongqing, 400712, China.</aa><em>zhoucy@swu.edu.cn</em></bibl><ab>From six different districts of Punjab, Pakistan, 85 isolates of Citrus tristeza virus (CTV) were collected and characterized based on coat protein gene (CPG) analysis. All isolates were collected from field trees showing various CTV symptoms such as decline in most citrus varieties, inverse pitting on some sour orange rootstocks below bud union, mild-to-moderate stem-pitting on the trunk of some sweet orange. The CTV CP gene of all isolates was amplified by reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) using CP gene-specific primers yielding 672 bp. The maximum disease incidence was found in sweet orange followed by mandarin and grapefruit. These isolates were then subjected to CPG/Hinf I restriction fragment length polymorphism (RFLP) analysis. Mixed infection of CTV isolates was found very common in the field tress in Pakistan. The most dominant CPG/Hinf I RFLP groups III, I and VI are the basic causal epidemic in Pakistan. Moreover, based on symptoms in the field trees, CPG/Hinf I RFLP groups III, I and VI are considered to be the obvious causes of decline and stem-pitting in Pakistan.</ab><index><de>coat proteins\disease incidence\epidemics\genes\genetic diversity\genetic markers\genetic variation\grapefruits\limes\mandarins\mixed infections\oranges\plant diseases\plant pathogens\plant viruses\restriction fragment length polymorphism\reverse transcriptase PCR\sour oranges\wild relatives</de><id>capsid proteins\genetic variability\genotypic variability\genotypic variation\multiple infections\Pakistan Punjab\phytopathogens\reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction\RFLP\RT-PCR\Rutales\Seville oranges\tangerines\viruses of plants</id><od>Citrus\Citrus aurantiifolia\Citrus aurantium\Citrus paradisi\Citrus reticulata\Citrus sinensis\Citrus tristeza virus\Closteroviridae\Closterovirus</od><gl>Pakistan\Punjab (Pakistan)</gl><up>viruses\Rutaceae\Sapindales\dicotyledons\angiosperms\Spermatophyta\plants\eukaryotes\Citrus\Closterovirus\Closteroviridae\positive-sense ssRNA viruses\ssRNA viruses\RNA viruses\plant viruses\Pakistan\South Asia\Asia\Developing Countries\Commonwealth of Nations</up><cc>FF003\FF610\ZZ360\ZZ395</cc><sc>0C\0P\0M\6C\CA\PE\HO\PL\QC\HQ\AA</sc></index><ex>20141111</ex><co>&#109; 2014 CAB International</co></record>
