<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record><an>7W03701955</an><pa>20113293474</pa><bibl><it>Journal article</it><au><au1>Park NamIl</au1><au2>Xu Hui</au2><au3>Li XiaoHua</au3><au4>Kim SunJu</au4><au5>Park SangUn</au5></au><av>Park, N. I.\Xu, H.\Li, X. H.\Kim, S. J.\Park, S. U.</av><do>Functional &#38; Integrative Genomics</do><et>Enhancement of flavone levels through overexpression of chalcone isomerase in hairy root cultures of Scutellaria baicalensis.</et><pb>Springer Berlin</pb><lp>Heidelberg</lp><cp>Germany</cp><yr>2011</yr><vl>11</vl><no>3</no><pp>491-496</pp><sn>1438-793X</sn><la>English</la><ur>http://www.springerlink.com/content/r7648n053001t225/</ur><oi>10.1007/s10142-011-0229-0</oi><re>29 ref.</re><aa>Department of Crop Science, College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Chungnam National University, 220 Gung-dong, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, 305-764, Korea Republic.</aa><em>supark@cnu.ac.kr</em></bibl><ab>A complementary DNA (cDNA) encoding Scutellaria baicalensis chalcone isomerase (SbCHI) was isolated using rapid amplification of cDNA ends polymerase chain reaction. After the treatment of wounding or methyl jasmonate, SbCHI transcripts were increased in S. baicalensis cell suspensions. SbCHI-overexpressed and SbCH-silenced transgenic hairy root lines were established by using an Agrobacterium rhizogenes-mediated system. SbCHI-overexpressed hairy root lines not only enhanced SbCHI gene expression but also produced more flavones (i.e., baicalin, baicalein, and wogonin) than the control hairy root line. In contrast, SbCHI-silenced hairy root lines reduced SbCHI transcripts and flavone production compared to those of the control hairy roots. In addition, the amount of wogonin in all hairy root cultures was increased compared to that of wild-type roots of S. baicalensis. Finally, this study showed the importance of CHI in flavone biosynthesis and the efficiency of metabolic engineering in S. baicalensis hairy roots.</ab><index><de>cell lines\cell suspensions\chalcone isomerase\complementary DNA\enzymes\flavones\gene expression\genes\genetic engineering\genetic transformation\genetically engineered organisms\hairy root cultures\in vitro culture\methyl jasmonate\plant growth regulators\transcription\transgenic plants</de><id>bacterium\cDNA\chalcone flavanone isomerase\DNA transcription\genetic manipulation\genetically engineered plants\genetically modified organisms\genetically modified plants\GEOs\GMOs\plant growth substances\plant hormones</id><od>plants\Rhizobium rhizogenes\Scutellaria baicalensis</od><up>eukaryotes\Rhizobium\Rhizobiaceae\Rhizobiales\Alphaproteobacteria\Proteobacteria\Bacteria\prokaryotes\Scutellaria\Lamiaceae\Lamiales\dicotyledons\angiosperms\Spermatophyta\plants</up><ry>9073-57-8\1211-29-6</ry><cc>FF003\FF020\FF060\FF170\WW100\ZZ360</cc><sc>7C\7B\7W\7Q\0C\0P\CA\HO\PL\ZG\QF\AA</sc></index><ex>20141111</ex><co>&#109; 2014 CAB International</co></record>
